Hi, this is Sean Hobson, and what we're talking about right now is the way to make a proper pass in the offense.
One of the best passes you can use, and one of the most effective passes, is a chest pass.
Now, it's called a chest pass for a reason.
You don't throw it at their head, and you don't throw it at their feet.
Instead, you're throwing it at their chest.
The reason you want to throw it in the chest area is because of the fact that that's where your hands most typically go.
That's also where you want to catch to shoot.
That's where you want to catch to pass.
Everything works out of this base area.
So, whenever you make a pass, you usually want to try to get it in the chest area.
Now, there's a couple mechanical things behind the chest pass.
One, obviously first we're going to fake the ball.
So, you always want to fake the pass off, then make the pass.
Whenever you make a pass, you want to try to keep your defender as far away as possible.
If I'm defending the ball, and Kyle's trying to throw the ball to that direction, we don't want him to throw with his right hand, because he's going to come through the defense.
Instead, we want him to throw his pass with the outside hand, away from his defender.
Same thing on the reverse side.
So you're going to throw strong hand pass or weak hand pass.
The other important thing is you're going to step when you pass it.
So you're going to fake, and you're going to step with your pass.
You're going to pop it off with your fingers, just almost like you were making a shot.
You're going to pop the pass.
You're not going to throw it and float the pass.
You're probably going to have to take one more step back.
We're going to show you at full speed here how to do some chest passes. Go. All right, you're good. Good.
All right, so that's the proper way to make a chest pass.
Step with it, pop the ball, and when you catch it, catch the ball in here, in the chest area.
That's a chest pass.